Loretta Yzquierdo

Lancaster, TX, United States ● Cell: 2145370652 ● retta0406@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Registered Nurse with 20+ years experience in clinical settings providing nursing care to diverse populations.

Specialized in cardiac care for over eight years.

Responsible RN with excellent communication skills demonstrated by 20+ years of experience in healthcare.

Work History

GI PACU PHASE 1, 09/2007 to Current

Baylor Scott & White Hospital – Lancaster, Texas

- Monitor patients who have had a GI procedures.
- Instructed patients and family members on proper discharge care.
- Received CEO Spirit of Excellence Award

Observation RN, 05/2005 to 09/2007

Baylor University Medical Center – Dallas, Texas

- Monitored patients requiring a 48 hour or less stay in hopital.
- Telemetry monitoring of those patients with need for cardiac monitoring.
- Instructed patients and family members on proper discharge care.

Telemetry Nurse Supervisor, 05/1997 to 05/2005

Baylor University Medical Center - Dallas, Texas

- Manage clinical and nonclinical staff for a 32 bed cardiac telemetry unit.
- Performed evaluations of staff.
- Ensured staff maintained all required licensure and certifications.

- Maintained schedule for all staff.
- Member of housewide cardiac and supervisors councils and unit council.

Telemetry Nurse, 06/1993 to 05/1997

Baylor University Medical Center – Dallas, Texas

- Primary care, assessment and evaluation of cardiac patients.
- Self-directed with astute judgment skills. High level of personal accountability.
- Instructed patients and family members on proper discharge care.
- Demonstrated ability to lead and motivate outstanding healthcare teams.

Education

Bachelor of Science: Nursing, 1997

University of Texas at Arlington - Arlington, Texas

Associate of Science: Nursing, 1993 El Centro College - Dallas, Texas

Skills

- BLS
- Cardiac Telemetry Monitoring
- Patient/family focused
- Problem resolution capability
- Chest pain management expert

- ACLS
- Preceptor
- Professional bedside manner
- Adept at prioritizing/managing deadlines
- Successfully directs staff meetings